Canada's Visual History Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Canada's Visual History Slide Collection
1974-1988
VRC 80
Yale University Arts Library
2.5
6 boxes
Collection consists of 2,400, 35 mm color slides of various topics of Canadian art, culture, and history. Produce for classroom use by the National Museum of Man and the National Film Board of Canada, Ottawa. Accompanying information booklets in English and French.
National Museum of Man (Canada)
National Film Board of Canada
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of 2,400, 35 mm color slides of various topics of Canadian art, culture, and history. Produce for classroom use by the National Museum of Man and the National Film Board of Canada, Ottawa. Accompanying information booklets in English and French.
Arrangement
Arranged by topic into 80 slide sets.
Arts, Canadian; Canada -- History; Slides; Reproductions
- Winnipeg, growth of a city, 1874-1914. Booklet by Alan F. J. Artibise. (Box 1)
- Immigration to western Canada, 1896-1914. Booklet by Donald Avery. (Box 1)
- 1919, a year of strikes. Booklet by David Jay Bercuson. (Box 1)
- Lumbering in the Ottawa Valley. Booklet by Terence Bren. (Box 1)
- Poverty in Montreal, 1897‐1929. Booklet by Terry Copp. (Box 1)
- Indian trade and ceremonial silver. Booklet by N. Jaye Goossen. (Box 1)
- The marriage furniture of Quebec. Booklet by Paul Louis Martin. (Box 1)
- British immigration to British North American, 1815-1860. Booklet by H.J.M. Johnston. (Box 1)
- Shipping and shipbuilding in the Maritime Provinces in the 19th century. Booklet by D.A. Muise and Charles Armour. (Box 1)
- The northern Ontario mining frontier, 1880-1920. Booklet by Gilbert A. Stelter. (Box 1)
- Transportation changes in the St. Lawrence-Great Lakes reion, 1828-1860. Booklet by Tulchinsky. (Box 1)
- Bell Island: a Newfoundland mining community. Booklet by Peter Near. (Box 1)
- The Blanketstiffs: itinerant railway construction workers, 1896-1914. Booklet by A. Ross McCormick. (Box 1)
- "Keeping British Columbia white": anti-Orientalism in the West, 1858-1949. Booklet by Stephen M. Beckow. (Box 1)
- Upper Canadian furniture. Booklet by Elizabeth Ingolfsrud. (Box 2)
- The ranching frontier in the Canadian West, 1874-1905. Booklet by David H. Breen. (Box 2)
- Urban development in central Canada to 1850. Booklet by J.M.S. Careless. (Box 2)
- The Asbestos Strike, 1949. Booklet by Jocelyn St. Pierre. (Box 2)
- French-speaking settlers on the prairies, 1870-1920. Booklet by Robert Painchaud. (Box 2)
- Marie Blanchet: Valleyfield cotton weaver, 1908. Booklet by Jacques Rouillard. (Box 2)
- The British Columbia mining frontier, 1880-1920. Booklet by Paul Phillips. (Box 2)
- The Mississauga of New Credit. Booklet by Donald B. Smith with the assistance of Bryan LaForme. (Box 2)
- Vancouver's early development. Booklet by Norbert MacDonald. (Box 2)
- Canada and the Boer War. Booklet by Carman Miller. (Box 2)
- Canada's northern frontier. Booklet by Richard J. Diubaldo. (Box 2)
- The seal and Labrador cod fisheries of Newfoundland. Booklet by Shannon Ryan. (Box 2)
- Canada's foreing policy, 1919-1939. Booklet by Norman Hillmer and Robert Bothwell (Box 2)
- Social life in New France. Booklet by W.J. Eccles. (Box 3)
- Prohibition in Canada. Booklet by Graeme Decarie. (Box 3)
- The Canadian campaign for woman suffrage. Booklet by Veronica Strong-Boag. (Box 3)
- The early development of hydroelectricity in Ontario. Booklet by Kenneth C. Dewar. (Box 3)
- The British child migration movement. Booklet by Joy Parr. (Box 3)
- Poverty and the working class in Toronto, 1880-1914. Booklet by Gregory S. Kealey and Linda Kealey. (Box 3)
- Life in the Western Canadian fur trade, 1770-1870. Booklet by Sylvia Van Kirk. (Box 3)
- Children and schools in 19thcentury Canada. Booklet by Harvey J. Graff and Alison Prentice. (Box 3)
- Cities in crisis: the Great Depression. Booklet by John. H. Taylor. (Box 3)
- Halifax, 1749-1849: garrison into metropolis. Booklet by David A. Sutherland. (Box 3)
- Thunder Bay: gateway between East and West. Booklet by Jean Morrison. (Box 3)
- Pre-industrial Montreal (ca. 1760-1850). Booklet by Paul-Andre Linteau and Jean-Claude Robert. (Box 3)
- London, Ontario: a case study in metropolitan evolution. Booklet by Frederick H. Armstrong and Daniel J. Brock. (Box 3)
- Clothing worn in Canada: changing fashions in the nineteenth century. Booklet by K.B. Brett. (Box 4)
- Printing in Canada. Booklet by E.J. Devereux. (Box 4)
- Loyalist architecture of British North America. Booklet by Stuart A. Smith. (Box 4)
- Defending New France: la petite guerre, 1660-1760. Booklet by Bernard Pothier. (Box 4)
- Ontario prehistory. Booklet by J.V. Wright. (Box 4)
- Blackfoot. Booklet by T.J.C. Brasser. (Box 4)
- Calgary: police post to oil capital. Booklet by David Breen. (Box 4)
- A century of French colonization in Canada. Booklet by Louise Dechêne. (Box 4)
- Saint John, the city and its poor, 1783-1877. Booklet by T.W. Acheson. (Box 4)
- Whaling in the Canadian Arctic. Booklet by Daniel Francis. (Box 4)
- The origins of the Ontario working class, 1867-1914. Booklet by Michael J. Piva. (Box 4)
- The electric telegraph in Canada, 1846-1902. Booklet by D.R. Richeson. (Box 4)
- Canadian Arctic prehistory. Booklet by Robert McGhee. (Box 4)
- Tommy Atkins, the British soldier in Canada, 1759-1870. Booklet by Carol M. Whitfield. (Box 4)
- Coal mining in Nova Scotia in 1925. Booklet by D.A. Muise. (Box 4)
- The early oil industry. Booklet by Marlynn Joliffe, Charles O. Fairbank, Jr., and Brian Arnott. (Box 5)
- Copper Eskimo. Booklet by David W. Zimmerly. (Box 5)
- Colonizing an eastern frontier: Compton County, Quebec. Booklet by J.I. Little. (Box 5)
- Through artist's eyes: war art in Canada. Booklet by H.A. Halliday. (Box 5)
- The Prairie grain economy. Booklet by F.A. Frieson and Ian McPherson. (Box 5)
- Immigrants in the city: Winnipeg's North End. Booklet by J. E. Rea. (Box 5)
- The Ile Royale Garrison, 1713-1745. Booklet by Margaret Fortier. (Box 5)
- Quebec workers and the Industrial Revolution in the late 19th century. Booklet by Fernand Harvey. (Box 5)
- Victorian pottery and porcelain in the Canadian home. Booklet by Elizabeth Collard. (Box 5)
- The prehistory of the Maritimes. Booklet by David Keenlyside. (Box 5)
- Canadian women and the Second World War. Booklet by Ruth Roach Pierson. (Box 5)
- The prehistory of Newfoundland and Labrador. Booklet by James A. Yuck. (Box 5)
- The home front, Canada, 1939-1945. Booklet by Fredric Gaffen. (Box 6)
- Early working-class life on the Praries. Booklet by Joe Cherwinski. (Box 6)
- [Oil and gas in Western Canada, 1900-1980. Booklet by A.W. Rasporich. MISSING] (Box 6)
- Northwest Rebellion of 1885. Booklet by Desmond Morton. (Box 6)
- The fur trade in Canada to 1787. Booklet by J.E. Foster and D.R. Richeson. (Box 6)
- Inuit of the Labrador Sea. Booklet by J. Garth Taylor. (Box 6)
- The transformation of work in the Maritimes, 1867-1925. Booklet by D.A. Muise. (Box 6)
- Institutions of confinement: the origins of Canadian mental hospitals and penitentiaries. Booklet by Daniel Francis and C. James Taylor. (Box 6)
- The prehistory of British Columbia. Booklet by Knut R. Fladmark. (Box 6)
- The Iroquois. Booklet by Thomas S. Abler. (Box 6)
- Québec prehistory. Booklet by J.V. Wright. (Box 6)
- Blacks in Atlantic Canada. Booklet by E.A. Spray. (Box 6)